本字幕由YYeTs人人影視翻譯第一版
由Matt K Fu 以基督徒角度作編修
僅供學習 禁止用於任何商業盈利行為
翻譯：sakura櫻  桑尼君  賀天天
翻譯：小琪777  和小蟹  蓬蓬裙
校對：威廉  蓬蓬裙   時間軸：言
後期：zzzyusa   校對&總監：不要叫我馬維斯
本劇改編自聖經  它們曾改變世界
本劇將始終保持《聖經》真諦
第08集-背叛者
《聖經》前情提要
Previously on The Bible.
猶太王國是由偉大的英雄們一手建立
Great heroes have forged the Jewish nation in faith.
摩西解放了子民  帶他們擺脫埃及人的奴役
Moses freed the people from Egyptian slavery.
主啊
Lord!
跟我走
Follow me!
約書亞帶領他的人民進入應許之地
Joshua led them into the promised land.
以色列  以色列
Israel! Israel!
大衛團結以色列人
David united the Israelites...
奪下了耶路撒冷
and delivered the city of Jerusalem.
但如今他們的後裔由羅馬統治
But now their descendants are ruled by Rome...
臣服於本丟．彼拉多之下
under Pontius Pilate.
羅馬人渣  羅馬小偷
Roman scum! Roman thieves!
數百人正要去見彼拉多長官
Hundreds are heading to see the Prefect Pilate.
什麼
What?
他們還未近他的身  就會成為亡魂
He'll have them cut down before they could get anywhere near him.
也該讓你們知道你們的主人為你們做了什麼
It's time you understood what your masters do for you.
彼拉多殘殺了成百上千的猶太人
Pilate has already massacred hundreds of Jewish people.
大祭司該亞法深感再多的騷亂
High Priest Caiaphas feels any further disorder
只會讓彼拉多繼續殺戮
could make Pilate kill again.
或者關閉聖殿
Or shut the temple.
在加利利省
In the province of Galilee,
耶穌已經引起轟動
Jesus has already been making waves.
倘若你渴望公義
If you hunger for righteousness,
跟隨我  你們必將達成所願
you will be filled... through me.
我聽說了一個年輕先知
I've had a report of a young prophet,
拿撒勒人耶穌
Jesus of Nazareth.
在加利利  有很多人跟從他
He has a big following in Galilee.
他能創造神跡
He works miracles.
耶穌為村民趕鬼
Jesus has cast out demons,
妙手回春
cured the sick...
甚至能起死回生
and has even raised the dead.
很多人都相信  他就是彌賽亞
Thousands believe he is the Messiah.
他們希望你能為他們的王
They want you to be their king,
猶太人的王
king of the Jews.
你能像帶領軍隊一般引領我們
You can lead us like an army.
動用武力不是解決辦法
This is not the way, not by force.
耶穌和他的跟隨者
Now Jesus and his followers...
正前往權力的中心  耶路撒冷
are heading to the center of power- Jerusalem.
加利利彌賽亞的出現
The Messiah from Galilee
和耶路撒冷逾越節的時間如此接近
and Jerusalem of Passover have time near.
彼拉多知道嗎
Does Pilate know?
聖經
禮拜日
逾越節前一周
逾越節是猶太人一年中最重要的節日
Passover is the biggest Jewish festival of the year.
成千上萬的人來到耶路撒冷感謝上帝
Thousands come to Jerusalem to thank God...
解救他們的祖先擺脫埃及人的奴役
for releasing their ancestors from Egyptian slavery.
看  是耶穌  彌賽亞
Look! It's Jesus! The Messiah!
帶上棕樹枝  彌賽亞  彌賽亞
Bring those palms! Messiah! Messiah!
耶穌進城在群眾中掀起了狂潮
Jesus ' entrance creates a storm.
他在那兒  他來了  和散那  和散那
There he is! There he is! Hosanna! Hosanna!
和散那  和散那
Hosanna! Hosanna!
先知撒迦利亞曾預言  猶太人的新王
The prophet Zechariah predicted that a new king of the Jews...
將騎著驢進城
would enter the city on a donkey.
和散那
Hosanna!
和散那  和散那
Hosanna! Hosanna!
他現在在哪兒
Where is he now?
他剛騎著驢進了城
He's just entered the city on a donkey.
瞧  你們的王來了
See, your king comes to you,
一身正氣  凱旋而來  而且謙卑有禮
righteous and victorious, humble...
還是騎著驢進城的
and riding on a donkey.
他要去哪裡
Where is he headed?
朝聖殿而去
Towards the temple.
這個來自加利利的擾亂者是個麻煩
This agitator from Galilee- he's trouble.
群眾呢  有什麼反應
The crowds- how are they responding?
羅馬人呢  有采取行動嗎
And the Romans, have they made any move yet?
-沒有  -遲早的事罷了
-No. -Hmm. Well, so far.
決不能讓他在逾越節搗亂
He must not interfere with Passover.
上帝會將他的忿怒降在所有人身上
God will bring his wrath down upon all of us.
如果群眾失控
And... who knows what Pilate will do...
誰知道彼拉多會做出什麼
if the crowds run out of control.
尼哥底母  和馬勒古一起去
Nicodemus, go with Malchus.
如果他進入聖殿  好好看著他
If he enters the temple, watch him.
好好看著
Do not blink.
我要知道一切情況  去吧
I need to know everything. Go.
天國就要來了
The kingdom is coming!
天國就要來了  這可是彌賽亞
The kingdom is coming! Messiah!
那是巴拉巴
That's Barabbas.
彌賽亞
Messiah!
以色列的王
King of Israel,
你為什麼不解救我們
why don't you make us free?
主啊  拯救我們遠離羅馬人
Save us from the Romans, Lord.
我們帶著和平而來  巴拉巴
We come in peace, Barabbas.
和散那  和散那
Hosanna! Hosanna!
讓開
Move.
閃開
Get out of the way!
退開
Get back!
聖殿是聖經之中最為神聖的地方
The temple is the holiest place in the Bible.
在節日裡
During festival times,
買賣獻祭的動物和兌換銀錢的交易
selling sacrificial animals and changing money...
十分興旺
has become a thriving business.
我來換換你這兒的錢
Change your money here!
二  五
Two, five-
都來這換吧
All change here!
換錢的到這裡
Exchange here!
你在幹什麼
What are you doing?
耶穌  別這樣
Jesus, please.
經上不是記著說
Is it not written-
慢著
Wait.
經上不是記著說
Is it not written-
"我的殿"
"My house-"
"我的殿必稱為萬國禱告的殿"嗎
"My house shall be called the house of prayer"?
但是你們
But you,
你們倒使他成為賊窩了
you have made it a den of thieves.
你是誰  有何資格這樣說教我們
Who are you to tell us this?
教律法的是我們  而不是你
We teach the law, not you.
你們只為身份高貴者禱告
You pray lofty prayers...
在聖殿之中裝出虔誠的模樣
and love your shows of piety in the temple.
假冒為善的人啊
Hypocrites.
你們不能事奉主的同時
You cannot serve God...
又事奉金錢
and money.
這太可惡了
This is outrageous.
你們卻什麼忙都幫不上
And you were little help.
他很聰明
He's clever.
民眾都尊崇他
The crowd worship him.
他有點不尋常
There is something unusual about him.
沒什麼不尋常的
There is nothing unusual about him,
除了有搞破壞的本事之外
apart from his ability to cause havoc.
如果他回來了  向他挑戰
If he returns, challenge him.
讓他的追隨們瞧瞧  他們的
Make his supporters see their Messiah...
是個頭腦多麼簡單的鄉下人
for the simpleminded peasant that he is.
星期一
距逾越節四天
逾越節前的一星期
In the week leading up to Passover,
猶太朝聖者們每天都來聖殿朝拜
Jews pilgrims visit the temple daily.
為窮人們捐錢吧
Ounce for the poor.
上帝保佑你
God bless you!
耶穌也回來了
Jesus also returns,
告誡更多的人
to preach to ever larger crowds.
比起一個財主
It's much harder for a rich person
進入神的王國
to enter the kingdom of God,
駱駝穿過針的眼
than it is,
還要更容易些呢
for a carmel to go through the eye of a needle.
最重要的是
The most important thing...
你應該像愛你自己一樣
is that you should love your neighbor...
愛你的鄰居
as you love yourself.
夫子
Teacher!
他們說你學識淵博  那麼告訴我們
They say you are learned. So tell us.
我們應該向羅馬人交稅嗎
Should we pay taxes to the Romans?
不
No!
圈套
It's a trap.
夫子
Well, teacher,
我們應該向羅馬人交稅嗎
should we... pay the Romans taxes...
不交  不交
Not pay! Not pay!
不交
Not pay!
以色列  以色列
Israel! Israel!
以色列
Israel!
告訴他
Tell him!
硬幣上的像是誰的
Whose face is on the coin?
是凱撒的
Caesar's.
那麼凱撒的物
Then give to Caesar...
當歸給凱撒
what is Caesar's...
神的物
and give to God...
當歸給神
what is God's.
大祭司  那個跟耶穌在一起的人
High Priest, that man there with Jesus,
他來找過我
he approached me.
他想幫我們
He wants to help us.
真的嗎  或許真用得上
Really? That could be useful.
你讓他占了上風
You let him get the better of you.
但我可能已經找到了對付他的辦法
Yet I may have found a way to deal with him.
星期三
距逾越節兩天
要順從
Teachers of the law,
律法師
obey them.
凡他們所吩咐你們的  你們都要遵行
Do everything they tell you,
但不要效法他們的行為
but don't do what they do.
因為他們能說不能行
They don't practice what they preach.
他們一切所作的事  都是要叫人看見
Everything they do is done for others to see.
只有一位是你們的父
You only have one father,
就是在天上的父
and he is in heaven.
只有一位是你們的師尊
You only have one teacher,
他...
and he...
就是基督
is the Christ.
以色列  以色列
Israel! Israel!
你看見這些雄偉的殿宇了嗎
Do you see all these great buildings?
將來在這裡
Not one stone of this place,
沒有一塊石頭是不被拆毀的
not one stone, will be left standing.
他說他要拆毀聖殿
He said he'll destroy the temple.
他說什麼
He said what?
將來沒有一塊石頭是不被拆毀的
Not one stone will be left standing.
他威脅說要拆毀聖殿
He threatens to destroy the temple.
我們必須迅速行動  而且不能聲張
We must move swiftly but softly.
我們不能公開抓捕他
We can not arrest him openly,
否則他的擁護者會暴動
or his his supporters will run riot.
不  不能在逾越節  不行
No, not on Passover. No.
不
No.
我們必須在逾越節前夜
We must bring him in quietly...
把他悄悄帶過來
at night before Passover.
馬勒古  你指給我看的
Malchus, what's the name of that
那個追隨者叫什麼
follower of his that you pointed out to me?
猶大  大祭司
Judas, High Priest.
猶大  是啊
Judas. Yes.
把他帶到這來見我
Bring him to me... here.
彼拉多宅邸
大人
Sir.
我們在吃飯呢
We're eating.
大人  有個猶太人在聖殿裡制造麻煩
Sir, a Jew has been causing trouble in the temple.
所以呢
So?
昨天他攻擊了兌換銀錢的人
Yesterday he attacked the money changers.
今天他又說要拆毀聖殿
Today he says he will destroy the temple.
他有眾多擁護者
He has a large number of supporters.
他叫什麼
What's his name?
他們稱他拿撒勒人耶穌
They call him Jesus of Nazareth.
我的僕人談起過他
My servants talk about him.
那是該亞法的事
He's Caiaphas' business.
但你要密切注意民眾的情況
But you keep an eye on the crowds.
若事態失控  我就關閉聖殿
If they start to get out of hand, I'll shut the temple.
管他是不是過節
Festival or no festival.
拉比
Rabbi.
我是尼哥底母
I am Nicodemus.
歡迎
Welcome.
我自願前來
I come here of my own accord.
大祭司並不知情
The High Priest knows nothing of this.
他來這裡幹嘛
What's he doing here?
顯然他不願意和我們同坐
Surely he doesn't want to sit with us.
猶大
Judas.
你那位來自加利利的朋友
Your friend from Galilee
引起了好一陣轟動啊
has caused quite a stir.
沒人能否認他有眾多追隨者
One cannot deny that he has followers,
尤其是一些沒怎麼受過教育的人
especially amongst the less well-educated element.
但你  猶大
But you, Judas-
我倒是很好奇
I'm intrigued.
他
He-
他有一種能力
He has a power.
很難用言語形容
It's hard for me to put into words.
他的能力就是制造麻煩
A power to cause trouble,
引起騷亂
to stir things up.
攻擊兌換銀錢之人
Attacking money changers.
威脅要拆毀聖殿
Threatening to destroy the temple-
那是我們的至聖所
the Holy of Holies.
如果他真是...
If he were...
神子
the Son of God-
如果
lf.
他會折辱神的聖殿嗎
Would he abuse the house of God?
真正的彌賽亞
The true Messiah...
會團結以色列  而非使其分裂
will unite Israel, not divide it.
你想對他怎麼樣
What do you want with him?
談談而已
Just to talk.
如果羅馬人介入此事
If the Romans step in,
你能想象那時的殺戮嗎
can you imagine the slaughter?
那將意味著聖殿的毀滅
It will mean the end of the temple,
信仰的毀滅
the end of our faith,
以及國家的終結
the end of our nation.
你想這樣嗎  猶大
Is that what you want, Judas?
猶大  你是他的朋友
Judas, you are his friend.
把他帶到這來  小心行事
Bring him here... discreetly.
讓我們共同阻止這一切
Let us try to stop this...
趁現在還來得及
while we still can.
那我有什麼好處
And what's in it for me?
很好
Good.
希望很快就能聽到你的好消息
We shall expect to hear from you presently.
他們說你能創造神跡
They say you can perform miracles,
說你見過神的國
that you have seen the kingdom of God.
你也能看見神的國
You can see the kingdom of God.
但你必須重生
But you must be born again.
重生  如何能重生
Born again? How can you be... born again?
你必須獲得新生
You must be reborn.
不是你的肉體
Not in the flesh,
而是你的靈
but in a spirit.
風隨著意思吹
The wind blows where it wishes.
你不曉得它從哪裡來
You don't k now where it comes from...
往哪裡去
or where it goes.
凡從聖靈生的  也是如此
And so it is when the Spirit enters you.
神
God...
愛世人
so loved the world...
甚至將他的獨生子賜給他們
that he gave his one and only son.
叫信他的人
Believe in him,
不至滅亡  反得永生
and you will have eternal life.
星期四
逾越節前一天
隨著逾越節愈發臨近
The closer it gets to Passover,
耶路撒冷局勢更加緊張
the tenser it gets in Jerusalem.
就在三十年前
Just 30 years ago,
羅馬人在逾越節游行期間殺害了數千人
the Romans killed thousands during Passover demonstrations.
羅馬盜賊  羅馬人渣
Roman thieves! Roman scum!
羅馬盜賊
Roman thieves!
羅馬盜賊  羅馬人渣
Roman thieves! Roman scum!
羅馬人渣
Roman scum!
場面太混亂了
This is a mess.
我必須通知彼拉多
I must inform Pilate.
從我擔任總督以來
Since I 've been prefect,
你們猶太人多次挑戰我耐心的底線
you Jews have tested my patience to breaking point.
現在我已忍無可忍
Now I 'm beyond it.
是的  但是  總督大人
Yes, but, prefect-
我正在說話
I'm speaking.
倘若動亂在明日再次發生
If disturbance took places a day and repeated tomorrow.
我會立即關閉聖殿
I will shut the temple immediately.
逾越節將被取消
There will be no Passover.
整個城市實行宵禁
I will put this city under curfew.
鎮壓一切叛亂
I will crush any rebellion.
我說得夠明白了嗎
Do I make myself absolutely clear?
主  我們感謝你
We thank you, Lord,
感謝你創造世間一切
by whose word everything comes to be.
阿門
Amen.
這是我死前  我們一起吃的
This is our last meal together...
最後一餐
before I die.
什麼意思
What do you mean?
我會被人出賣給我的敵人
I 'm going to be betrayed to my enemies.
被逮捕
Arrested...
並處以死刑
and condemned to death.
馬勒古  猶太有什麼消息嗎
Malchus, any word from Judas?
沒有  大祭司
Nothing, High Priest.
我不會再等了
I won't wait any longer.
馬勒古  我們今晚就把這個假先知抓起來
Malchus, we arrest this false prophet tonight.
我們怎麼知道他是假先知
How do we know he is a false prophet?
他符合
Has he fulfilled...
我們經文中所描述的
any of the signs of a true Messiah
真正的彌賽亞的特征嗎
as written in our scriptures?
尼哥底母  他符合嗎
Well, Nicodemus, has he?
他將依據我們的律法受審
He will be tried according to our law.
我們得除掉他  否則羅馬人會毀滅一切
We remove this man or the Romans destroy everything.
除掉
Remove?
處死
Execute?
沒錯  尼哥底母
Yes, Nicodemus.
用這個鄉下人的命
The life of one peasant...
換取上帝之國的未來
for the future of God's nation.
你們不要害怕
Don't be afraid.
要相信上帝
Trust in God.
也要相信我
Trust in me also.
我要去的地方  你們知道怎麼走
You know the way to where I'm going.
我們都不知道你往哪裡去
We don't know where you are going,
怎麼會認得路呢
how can we know the way?
我就是道路
I am the way,
真理
the truth...
和生命
and the life.
拿去
Take it.
吃吧
Eat.
這
This-
這是我的身體
This is my body.
這是我的血
This is my blood.
通過這樣
Remember me...
記住我
by doing this.
我要去天父那裡了
I'm going to the Father.
但我將一直與你們同在
But I will always be with you.
現在我要告訴你們
But now I must tell you...
你們中間有一個人
that one of you here...
要賣我了
will betray me.
是誰
Who?
那個吃了它的人
Whoever eats this.
我不會  我不會出賣你的
I will not. I will not betray you.
快做吧
Do it quickly.
讓他走
Let him go.
今夜你們都要跌倒
You will all fall away.
拉比
Rabbi.
我永不跌倒
I will not fall away.
我願意為你舍命
I will lay down my life for you.
你真願意嗎
Will you?
我願意
I will.
彼得
Peter,
我要告訴你
I tell you...
雞叫以先
before dawn,
你要三次不認我
you will deny me...three times.
猶大  他在哪
Judas. Where is he?
-我...  -你究竟知不知道他在哪
- I... - Do you know where he is now?
我知道他會去哪
I know where he's going.
帶我的侍從找到他
Lead my servant to him.
客西馬尼花園
醒醒
Wake up.
別睡著了
And keep awake.
時辰已到
The time has come.
你們心靈固然願意  肉體卻軟弱了
The spirit is willing, but the flesh is weak.
我必須要禱告
I must pray.
我父啊
Father.
我知道
I know...
一切
it must be...
都照你的旨意
as you will it.
父啊  帶走我的靈魂吧
Father, take this from me.
寬恕我
Spare me.
神啊  你定會滿意我的所為
Lord, I know you will please with me.
因你一直誠心扶持我
For you sustain me in sincerity.
感謝你們  我們的祖先
We thank you, our ancestors,
感謝你們的庇佑
for watching over us.
父啊
Father.
稱頌我主
Praise the Lord.
以色列之神
God of Israel.
永生不死
Everlasting and everlasting.
阿們  阿們
Amen and amen.
如果這是你的旨意  父啊
If you will it, Father.
如果這是你的旨意
If you will it,
我必完成
your will...
你的旨意
is mine.
你來要作的事  就作吧
Do what you came for.
叛徒
Traitor!
抓住他  抓住他
Take him. Take him.
不
No!
快跑  耶穌
Run, Jesus!
跑  快跑
Run! Run!
快跑  耶穌
Run, Jesus!
彼得
Peter.
凡動刀的
He who lives by the sword...
必死在刀下
dies by the sword.
快跑
Run!
快點  走  快走
Come on, you! Move! Move it!
把他帶回去
Take him back.
這人怎麼處置
What about this one?
滾遠點
Get out of here!
快來
Come on.
我不會拋下耶穌的
I won't leave Jesus.
-彼得  -快走吧
- Peter - Come on!
快走  馬利亞
Come on, Mary.
別停下
Keep moving!
走快點
Quickly!
耶穌
Jesus!
起來
Get up!
夠了
Enough!
接著走  別停下
Keep him moving.
叫你口出狂言
We'll teach you to blaspheme.
過來
Come on!
-告訴該亞法我們抓到耶穌了  -是
- Tell Caiaphas we have Jesus. - Yes, sir.
你不用跟了
Not you.
"因此夜間的審判包括死刑
"Therefore night trials involving death penalty
不得在安息日前夜
may not be held on the eve of Sabbath...
或是其他宗教節日前夜進行"
or on the eve of a feast day."
首席辯士說
The best scholar say
審判只能在白晝進行
we must hold our trials by daylight.
但我們今晚就審判
But the trial is tonight.
你不能這麼幹
You cannot go through with this.
這不合法
It is not legal.
我們的辯士說
Our scholar say
審判必須在白天在法庭上公開進行
it must be in court, in daylight, in public!
必須這麼做
It is necessary.
為什麼要這麼趕
Why the rush?
你明知道的
You know why.
彼拉多會關閉聖殿
Pilate will close the temple.
我們必須除掉這個耶穌
We must be rid of this Jesus.
如果他真的是人們所說的那個人呢
But what if he really is who they say he is?
我們會准確地判斷這事的
We are to decide precisely that.
現在  按上帝指引的做
now, with God's guidance.
上帝要求我們遵守律法
God demands we obey the law.
那我提醒你  律法是這麼寫的
Let me remind you what the law says.
任何對祭司或審判表示蔑視的人
Anyone who shows contempt for the judge or for the priest...
格殺勿論
shall be put to death.
任何人
Anyone.
告訴我
Tell me.
請告訴我
Speak to me.
為什麼放任他們如此對你
Why letting them do this to you?
別再向前了  退下
No, no, no. Get back.
看到那個被捕的人了嗎
Have you seen the man they arrested?
-看到那個被捕的人了嗎  -退下
- Have you seen the man they arrested?  -Get back.
同胞們
Brothers.
感謝各位深夜前來
Thank you for coming at this hour.
如果不是要緊事
You know I would not have asked you...
我也不會如此興師動眾
if it were not so serious.
讓他起來
Get him up.
拿撒勒人耶穌
Jesus of Nazareth,
你被指控褻瀆上帝
you are charged with blasphemy.
馬利亞
Mary?
Mary.
出什麼事了  我的兒子呢
What has happened? Where is my son?
耶穌被捕了
Jesus has been arrested.
被捕
Arrested?
但我們不知道他被抓到哪去了
But we don't know where they have taken him.
被捕
Arrested?
在夜裡嗎
At night?
他們是秘密行動
They want to keep it secret.
不希望引起民眾抗議
They don't want any protests.
他利用魔鬼的力量去治愈疾病
He has employed demons... to heal.
他還威脅說
He has threatened...
要摧毀上帝的聖殿
to destroy the temple of our Lord.
同胞們  在審判之前
Brothers, we must listen...
我們必須傾聽
before we judge.
所以  我請先知來
And so I invite the prophet...
說一說
to speak.
請告訴我們  上帝向你傳達的話
Tell us the message you bring from God.
沒有嗎
Nothing?
無話可說嗎  當然
Nothing to say? Surely.
告訴我們
Tell us this.
你是不是天選之子
Are you... the Chosen One?
你是不是神子
Are you the Son of God?
我是
I am.
你們將會看見人子
And you will see me coming...
駕著天上的雲降臨
with the clouds of heaven,
坐在那權能者的右邊
sitting at the right hand of God.
真是無法容忍
This is repulsive!
和上帝一起  騙子
With God? Impostor!
蠢材  僭妄者
Fool! Blasphemer!
大家都聽見了
We have heard enough.
裁決結果只有一個
There is only one verdict.
他有罪嗎
Guilty?
這是不對的
This is wrong.
這給我們的公會帶來恥辱
This brings shame on our council.
不是嗎
Does it not?
同胞們
Brothers.
此人被判處死刑
The sentence is death.
《聖經》下集預告
Next time on The Bible.
長官  我們需要您的幫助
Prefect, we need your help.
我們判決了一名非常危險的犯人
We have convicted a dangerous criminal.
他活一日  就是一日的威脅
He is an immediate threat.
他叫什麼
His name.
拿撒勒人耶穌
Jesus of Nazareth.
你是猶太人的王嗎
Are you the king of the Jews?
我的國
My kingdom...
不屬於這世界
is not of this world.
此人不過是有被人蠱惑了
He's guilty of nothing more than being deluded.
他侵犯了我們神聖的律法
He has broken our sacred laws.
拿撒勒人耶穌被判有罪
Jesus of Nazareth has been found guilty.
拿回你們的臭錢吧
Take back your money!
你認識他  你稱他拉比
You know him. You called him Rabbi.
我不認識此人
He's nothing to do with me.
他們會殺了他的
They're going to kill him.
釘死他
Crucify him!
你必因此事後悔終生
You'll live to regret this.
一周之後就沒人會記得他是誰了
He'll be forgotten in a week.
你本應是他的磐石
You were supposed to be his rock.
我辜負了他  如今也無法請求他的原諒
I failed him. Now I can't ask him to forgive me.
父啊
Father.
赦免他們
Forgive them...
因為他們所作的  他們不曉得
for they know not what they do.